# Ivan Monge

Mechatronic Engineer Software Management and Engineering

Casa Grande AZ

442-288-8132

ivan m 9@hotmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivan-monge-/

https://ivanmongebadilla.github.io/portfolio/

I have a bachelor's degree in Mechatrnonic Engineering and a master's degree in software management and engineering. I have been passionate about software development since I was doing my bachelor's degree and during my engineer career, I have developed different software and scripts (VBA, JavaScript, Python) to my team and other teams to automate repetitive tasks. I also developed a computer vision system from scratch using python. I have more than 6 years of experience in the automotive industry, but I am looking for my opportunity to change path to software development.

#### Soft Skills

- Creative Problem Solving
- Collaboration & TeamWork
- Multitasking
- Critical Thinking
- Self-Motivation

- Work Ethic
- Fast Learner
- Persistence

### **Technical Skills**

- HTML
- CSS
- SASS
- React
- Redux
- React Router

- Context
- JavaScript
- Python
- React Native
- MongoDB

- Scapy
- Tkinter
- OpenCV
- Tanstack/Query
- NodeJs
- Bootstrap

# **Projects**

Cockatil Finder. Application to find the instructions of different cocktails. This was developed with React and uses the cocktaildb API. https://ivan-monge-drink-app.netlify.app/

**E-Commerce.** This application was developed with React using Context, Reactstrap, React Router, Tanstack/React-Query, etc. Data is fetched from Fake Store API. https://ivanmonge-ecommerceapp.netlify.app/

**Hotel Reviewer.** Webpage where you can review hotels and also leave comments. This application uses json-server to fetch the hotel and reviews. Also, json-server auth is used for authentication. https://github.com/ivanmongebadilla/auth-app

**Crossfit Webpage.** Application developed with html, SASS and JavaScript. It is fully responsive for different viewports. https://ivanmongebadilla.github.io/crossfitWebpage/

**Computer Vision System.** This application was developed for a private company to detect printed lot numbers in the packaging bottles. Developed with python, tkinter, OpenCV. <a href="https://github.com/ivanmongebadilla/python-CVS">https://github.com/ivanmongebadilla/python-CVS</a>

**Training Application.** React Native application using Express backend and MongoDB. This application also uses redux to manage the store. https://github.com/ivanmongebadilla/FinalHonors

## Experience

12/2022 - CURRENT

ADAS Production Engineer / Lucid Motors, Casa Grande AZ.

10/2021 - 12/2022

Automation Engineer / Gowan Milling, Yuma AZ.

03/2021 - 10/2021

Electrical/Software Design Engineer / Kenworth, Mexicali B.C.

01/2019 - 02/2021

PACCAR Engine Liaison / Kenworth, Mexicali B.C.

09/2017 - 02/2019

Electrical/Software Liaison Engineer / Kenworth, Mexicali B.C.

04/2016 - 09/2017

Electrical Design Engineer / Kenworth, Kirkland WA.

## **Education**

08/2011 - 02/2016

Bachelor's Degree Mechatronic Engineering / CETYS, Mexicali B.C.

09/2019 - 12/2020

Master Software Management and Engineering / Universidad Tecnológica Latinoamericana

10/2022 - 03/2023

Full Stack Web and Mobile Development / Nucamp Coding Bootcamp

## **Certifications**

- Advanced CSS and SASS Udemy
- React The Complete Guide 2023 Udemy
- SLC 500 Controller Rockwell Automation
- Factory Talk Rockwell Automation
- Design for Six Sigma PACCAR Inc.
- Lean Manufacturing PACCAR Inc.